<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[A romarchives news.]]></title><description><![CDATA[There will be announces of new added games or whatever.]]></description><link>http://localhost:3000</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 06:40:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><language><![CDATA[en]]></language><item><title><![CDATA[Hello, RSS!]]></title><description><![CDATA[I setted RSS, so all big events will be announced.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Hello, RSS!</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 10:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[All the original S.T.A.L.K.E.R. games are avaible to download]]></title><description><![CDATA[All the 3 games are avaible: S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Clear Sky (2008),
 S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Call of Pripyat (2009),
 S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl (2007).
 Download and play this games, maybe you would like them or you already playing them!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">All the original S.T.A.L.K.E.R. games are avaible to download</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 11:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello, VR!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Added VR systems as "Bjorn LOVR" or "PICO OS" or "Meta QuestOS" (Quest's OS). Also added tag VR for Android's Google Cardboard and PCVR in Microsoft Windows. Added popular games such as Job Simulator or Beat Saber.]]></description><link>http://romarchive.zapto.org:88/Meta%20QuestOS/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://romarchive.zapto.org:88/Meta%20QuestOS/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 13:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bye, Emulator.js]]></title><description><![CDATA[Starting on now, there will be only external, hosted in this website, emulators. Problem with emulator.js is it's sometimes not even want to work. I will try to find or develop emulators for some systems, no more emulator.js!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">Bye, Emulator.js</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 09:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[GUIDE: How to launch over 10000 games on your iPhone!]]></title><description><![CDATA[All the process is kinda simple, all you need is this two apps:
- RetroArch
-  Owlfiles
Let's prepare it all! Launch 'Owlfiles', go to section 'Connections' and click on bolt icon, then add connection. You will see so much icons, but we need FTP. Make sure to NOT select SFTP. In displayed name, type anything that you can remember. In host name, type 'romarchive.zapto.org', in port '14118'. In connection type, select 'Active'. Right now you can easily surf roms, but that's not what we need. Now, launch RetroArch. For first time fonts can be not downloaded, and everything will appear glitched. Do NOT click anything, and in 10-20 seconds everything will be fine.
Running games
Press 'Load content', then 'Open...' and file explorer will be opened in some directory. Go to root directory, then 'Owlfiles', then name that you typed. Now select almost any console, I would recommend 'Sega Mega Drive' then open ANYTHING there. You will be prompted to select core, select first one. If not worked, do same with different cores. Have fun!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">GUIDE: How to launch over 10000 games on your iPhone!</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 11:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who uses tape and why it's future]]></title><description><![CDATA[In December 2020, IBM Research and Fujifilm presented a prototype of a 580 terabyte LTO cartridge. A small magnetic tape cassette holds information equal to several dozen regular HDDs or 120,000 DVDs. Magnetic tapes appeared almost a hundred years ago, and computer files have been recorded on them since 1952. Even our mothers changed reels on mainframes in Soviet research institutes. And in 2021, films remain the cheapest storage medium with storage costs about 6 times lower than on HDDs. Since film has practically disappeared from the consumer market, many do not even know how rapidly this technology is developing. Magnetic tape reels manufactured by Orwo (GDR) in the Soviet mainframe ES-1020 computer at the Department of Applied Mathematics of the Physics and Mathematics Department of the Leningrad Polytechnic Institute, mid-1980s. The read/write speed was 2 meters (64 kilobytes) per second, source A little history In general, magnetic tape was invented by the German chemist Fritz Pflömer in 1928, that is, 93 years ago. He was the first to guess to make a magnetic powder coating from iron oxide on thin paper using glue. The first tape was manufactured by the German concern BASF. At first it was used to record sound, and in the 50s experiments began on recording video, as well as digital computer data, and the second option was considered much more promising, because magnetic video cassettes still could not compare with film in terms of image quality. The world's first digital data tape was written and read by the Uniservo I magnetic heads for the UNIVAC I computer in 1951. That half-inch (12.65 mm) wide tape recorded data at a density of 100 characters per inch. Then IBM took over and released 7-track tapes of the same half-inch width. The IBM 726 model stored 2 megabytes on a reel. The device was rented for $850 per month, source Then 9-track tapes were developed for the IBM System/360. Nine tracks allowed exactly one byte (8 information bits plus 1 control bit) to be recorded in each position of the tape. These reels became the computer standard for 30 long years, including for Soviet computers. Recording Density Recording density was constantly growing: up to 200, 556, 800 characters per inch, then for 9-track tapes it was 800, 1600 and 6250 bytes per inch. By the 70s, recording had reached such a density that it became possible to reduce the tape width. This is how the first compact cassettes and cartridges appeared. Linear Tape-Open (LTO) is one of the modern cartridge standards that features the highest recording density. Current tapes are produced with a barium ferrite (BaFe) coating. In each new generation of LTO, the particles became smaller and smaller, forming narrower data tracks. In December 2020, Fujifilm and IBM announced the first model with a strontium ferrite (SrFe) coating. The particle size decreased by 60%. The recording density of tapes can be compared with that of HDDs, because they use a similar principle of storing magnetized bits in a layer of media on a substrate. The recording density of HDDs has slowed down its growth in the last decade. High hopes are placed only on thermal magnetic recording (HAMR), where the figure exceeds 2 Tbit/in². LTO is far from such indicators. But even with the existing density, cartridges significantly outpace HDDs in terms of total information volume, because the area of ​​​​the tape on the reel is much larger than the area of ​​​​the pancakes in the hard drive. The cartridge design allows 32 reading heads to be used simultaneously, which gives an advantage in terms of read and write speed compared to HDD. The main thing is that the recording density on film continues to grow exponentially, by about 33% per year. That is, the doubling of the storage capacity occurs approximately every two to three years. In comparison, progress in the production of hard drives has slowed down significantly (if HAMR does not live up to expectations). According to IBM, there are approximately 345,000 exabytes of data stored on magnetic tape in the world today. This means that tape is currently the primary storage medium of human civilization. And it looks like this will continue for the foreseeable future.]]></description><link>https://habr.com/ru/companies/vdsina/articles/542002/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://habr.com/ru/companies/vdsina/articles/542002/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 17:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Кто использует плёнку и почему за этим будущее]]></title><description><![CDATA[В декабре 2020 года IBM Research и Fujifilm представили прототип картриджа LTO на 580 терабайт. Небольшая кассета с магнитной лентой вмещает информацию, эквивалентную нескольким десяткам обычных HDD или 120 000 DVD. Магнитные ленты появились почти сто лет назад, а компьютерные файлы на них записываются с 1952 года. Еще наши мамы меняли катушки на мэйнфреймах в советских НИИ. А в 2021 году кинопленка остается самым дешевым носителем информации, стоимость хранения на которой примерно в 6 раз ниже, чем на HDD. Поскольку кинопленка практически исчезла с потребительского рынка, многие даже не знают, насколько стремительно развивается эта технология. Катушки с магнитной лентой производства Orwo (ГДР) в советском мэйнфрейме ЕС-1020 на кафедре прикладной математики физико-математического факультета Ленинградского политехнического института, середина 1980-х годов. Скорость чтения/записи составляла 2 метра (64 килобайта) в секунду, источник Немного истории Вообще магнитную ленту изобрел немецкий химик Фриц Пфлёмер в 1928 году, то есть 93 года назад. Он первым догадался сделать магнитное порошковое покрытие из оксида железа на тонкой бумаге с помощью клея. Первую ленту изготовил немецкий концерн BASF. Сначала ее использовали для записи звука, а в 50-х годах начались эксперименты по записи видео, а также цифровых компьютерных данных, причем второй вариант считался гораздо более перспективным, ведь по качеству изображения магнитные видеокассеты все равно не могли сравниться с пленкой. Первую в мире цифровую ленту с данными записали и считывали магнитные головки Uniservo I для компьютера UNIVAC I в 1951 году. Та лента шириной в полдюйма (12,65 мм) записывала данные с плотностью 100 символов на дюйм. Затем IBM взялась за дело и выпустила 7-дорожечные ленты той же ширины в полдюйма. Модель IBM 726 хранила 2 мегабайта на катушке. Устройство сдавалось в аренду за 850 долларов в месяц, источник Затем были разработаны 9-дорожечные ленты для IBM System/360. Девять дорожек позволяли записывать ровно один байт (8 информационных бит плюс 1 контрольный бит) в каждую позицию ленты. Эти катушки стали компьютерным стандартом на долгие 30 лет, в том числе и для советских компьютеров. Плотность записи Плотность записи постоянно росла: до 200, 556, 800 символов на дюйм, затем для 9-дорожечных лент она составляла 800, 1600 и 6250 байт на дюйм. К 70-м годам запись достигла такой плотности, что стало возможным уменьшить ширину ленты. Так появились первые компакт-кассеты и картриджи. Linear Tape-Open (LTO) — один из современных стандартов картриджей, отличающийся самой высокой плотностью записи. Современные ленты производятся с покрытием из феррита бария (BaFe). В каждом новом поколении LTO частицы становились все меньше и меньше, образуя все более узкие дорожки данных. В декабре 2020 года Fujifilm и IBM анонсировали первую модель с покрытием из феррита стронция (SrFe). Размер частиц уменьшился на 60%. Плотность записи лент можно сравнить с HDD, поскольку они используют схожий принцип хранения намагниченных бит в слое носителя на подложке. Плотность записи HDD замедлила свой рост в последнее десятилетие. Большие надежды возлагаются только на термомагнитную запись (HAMR), где этот показатель превышает 2 Тбит/дюйм². LTO далек от таких показателей. Но даже при существующей плотности картриджи значительно опережают HDD по общему объему информации, поскольку площадь ленты на катушке значительно больше площади блинов в жестком диске. Конструкция картриджа позволяет использовать 32 считывающие головки одновременно, что дает преимущество по скорости чтения и записи по сравнению с HDD. Главное, что плотность записи на пленку продолжает расти экспоненциально, примерно на 33% в год. То есть удвоение емкости накопителя происходит примерно каждые два-три года. Для сравнения, прогресс в производстве жестких дисков существенно замедлился (если HAMR не оправдает ожиданий). По данным IBM, сегодня в мире на магнитной ленте хранится около 345 000 эксабайт данных. Это значит, что лента в настоящее время является основным носителем информации человеческой цивилизации. И, похоже, так будет продолжаться в обозримом будущем.]]></description><link>https://habr.com/ru/companies/vdsina/articles/542002/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://habr.com/ru/companies/vdsina/articles/542002/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 17:28:30 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>